Adrienne Hein

Full-Stack Web Developer San Diego, CA aehein.com adrienne.hein@gmail.com heina::linkedin | adriennehein::github 971.207.7885

Full-stack developer with exceptional attention to detail and extensive client-facing experience. UI/UX enthusiast with a passion for clean design. Creative problem solver who thrives on change and challenges, and is highly adaptable in high-pressure situations, including project deadlines and conflict resolution.

Education

LEARN Academy

Full-Stack Web Development Program
Ruby/Rails & JS immersion program
Oregon State University (GPA: 3.97)
B.A. 2011; Summa Cum Laude, German
Honor Roll for eight consecutive terms
Awarded SMART Grant; Outstanding Senior

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, SQL, PHP Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, Foundation, Material UI Tools/Libraries: React, jQuery, PostgreSQL, Git, Docker, Wordpress Strategies: Pair Programming, MVC, Object-Oriented Programming, Behavior-Driven Development, Agile

Software: Atom, G Suite, Microsoft Office, pgAdmin, Photoshop,

Replyify, Sketch, Trello

Media Literacy Tool

Ruby/Rails full-stack app that won Most Innovative at the WWC Hackathon. Used Git workflo. www.devpost.com/adriennehein media-literacy.herokuapp.com/

Projects Trip & Share

Ruby/Rails API with React.js. Responsible for site design, style, wireframes; used relational database, Git, Rspec, Reactstrap http://tripandshare.herokuapp.com
Login: example@tripandshare.com, password

Hyrax

Wrote integration tests for opensource content repository framework https://github.com/samvera/

Experience

Web Developer

Off Leash K9 Huntsville

September, 2018

- Responsible for all development for http://olk9huntsville.com
- · Built dynamic templates, pulling data from custom CMS API with little documentation (Polymath)
- Translated PSD mockups and UX wireframes into responsive, dynamic website
- · Used PHP 7, Dwoo, HTML5, SCSS, Gulp, jQuery, Docker, Bitbucket, external plugins

Web Developer Contractor

Indubitable Media

April, 2018 - Present

- Building templates for Wordpress and other CMS API integration
- · Using SCSS, Foundation, Gulp, jQuery, external plugins
- · Working from wireframes with creative license and converting PSD mockups into responsive pages
- Designed, coded, and integrated reusable features (calendar, gallery, navigation)

Software Development Intern

Notch8

April, May 2018

- Full-Stack Ruby/Rails internship at web application consultancy
- · Working on open-source digital content management library system for non-profit
- Integration testing with Capybara, Selenium & Rspec; testing Rails application with complex file structure
- Project management using Docker, GitLab

- · Sold \$645k in first year, awarded Top Seller recognition & recognized as All Star for outstanding customer service
- Drove extra \$10k/month through loyal client relationships—used new technology to boost sales outside workplace
- Developed creative problem solving skills to resolve issues surrounding customer satisfaction, missing merchandise, and tactful return processing
- Excelled in competitive commission environment, while maintaining strong, collaborative relationships with coworkers

Editor & Content Lead

Hatch Innovation

2014 - 2015

- Planned, edited content for non-profit's monthly newsletter—scheduled and led weekly editorial calendar meetings, by coordinating with staff and fellows to select articles.
- Formulated newsletters, wrote articles, and regularly edited and posted content onto multiple Hatch-affiliated websites. Participated in weekly marketing meetings, ensuring social media presence was consistent.
- Coordinated fundraising event for 150 people—produced promotional content, post-event coverage, and liaised between volunteers and local businesses.

Various Roles

Nordstrom Rack

2011-2015

- Experience in nearly all sides of business— managed team of 10 people; resolved complicated customer issues sometimes spanning multiple shifts; analyzed sales and department goals on weekly basis; performed bi-weekly manager-in-charge shifts in large downtown store
- Led inventory team and assessed product demand and processing strategies